#Encodergasm Presents
It was raining that day as well.
（ジュリア）
雨が降ってた　あの日も
You didn't come because of the rain?
（スパイク）
来なかったのは雨のせいか？
I was supposed to kill you.
私は あなたを殺すはずだった
That day...
あの日―
...if I had killed you...
あなたを殺せば
私は自由になれるはずだった
...I would have been free.
So why didn't you?
（スパイク）なぜ やらなかった？
Why did you choose to be pursued?
なぜ追われる道を選んだ？
Why...
（ジュリア）なぜ―
...did you...
私を愛したの？
...love me?
Let's just run away somewhere.
このまま どこかに逃げよう
Truly escape from this world...
本当に この世界から抜け出して
誰も いない所へ
...and go where no one else is.
Just the two of us...
２人だけで
（シン）あっ…
What about him?
（ビシャス）やつは どうした？
He got away.
（シン）逃がしました
All our men were defeated, we ran out of weapons...
味方は全て倒され 武器も底を尽き
手立てを失い…
...and lost all means to...
Why did you come back?
（ビシャス）なぜ戻ってきた？
Where is Julia?
ジュリアは どこにいる？
I don't know.
私には…
Shin.
（ビシャス）シン
（シン）ハッ
リンの二の舞には なるな
Don't follow in Lin's footsteps.
Keep going, and pass the place.
そのまま やり過ごせ
What?
何？
Someone might have gotten here already.
もう 手が回ってるかもしれない
Wait here.
ここで待ってろ
Annie?
アニー
（アニー）はあ
I told them that you weren't here.
（アニー）
来てないって言ったのにさ
That you were already dead.
あんたは もう死んでるって
I told them...
そう言ったんだけどさ
（スパイク）しゃべるな
Don't talk.
（アニー）うっ！
ビシャスが
長老たちを やったってさ
Vicious...
...killed off the elders, they said.
Everyone has lost sense of where they want to be.
みんな 糸の切れた凧(たこ)みたいに
行き場を無くしちまってるよ
Just like kites with no strings.
I see... you were able to meet Julia...
そうか　ジュリアに会えたんだね
I'm glad...
よかった
Annie!
（ジュリア）アニー！
It's... rather chilly... today...
今日は やけに―
冷えるねえ
You don't need weapons like that just to run away.
どこかへ逃げるために
そんな武器は いらないわ
You're going to go.
行くの？
I'll go with you.
一緒に行くわ
Until the very end, I'll be with you.
最後まで 一緒に
I'm sorry.
悪いな ちょっと騒がすぜ
I'm gonna make a bit of a scene.
You sure are a lucky woman.
（ジェット）運のいい女だな
Really.
（フェイ）
本当　いい時に帰ってきて
いい具合に巻き込まれて…
I came back just at the right time, and got involved in just the right way.
本当 ついてるわ
I really am lucky.
The Red-Tail won't be mobile for a while.
（ジェット）レッドテイルは
当分 動かせんぞ
You're doing pretty well yourself...
あんたも踏んだり蹴ったりね
...getting the short end of the stick and all.
とばっちりばっか受けちゃって
He's probably not coming back, you know that?
もう戻って来ないんじゃない？
どっかで やられちゃったかも
He might have been offed somewhere already.
Maybe so.
かもしれん
But, so what?
だから何だ？
Do you want me to go looking for him?
俺に捜しに行けか？
冗談じゃねえ
You've got to be kidding!
He went off to do away with his past!
あいつは
自分の過去のために行ったんだ
You made him go.
自分で行かせたくせに
My leg was shot, my ship is busted!
脚を撃たれて 船までやられて
そうさ 迷惑ばっかりだ
Hell, yeah!  He was nothing but trouble!
Like I care!
俺の知ったことか
So what kind of a woman was Julia?
どんな女だった？
ジュリアって女は
A normal woman.
（フェイ）普通の女よ
A beautiful, dangerous but normal woman that you can't leave alone.
きれいで危なくて ほっとけない
普通の女
I see.
（ジェット）そうか
Like a devilish angel...
悪魔みたいな天使か
天使みたいな悪魔かも
...or maybe an angelic devil.
This way!
こっちだ
Get down!
伏せろ！
Julia!
ジュリア！
Hey!
おい！
Where is Spike now?
スパイクは今 どこにいる？
All organisms...
（ブル）生きるものは
命あるものは―
...all beings with life...
...all have their own stars.
全て自分の星を持っている
ああん？
The moment a new life is born...
命が生まれた瞬間に
星も生まれ―
...a new star is born, and becomes the guardian star.
そして守り星となる
This star we stand on is someone's guardian star as well.
この星も誰かの守り星
That red star, that blue star...
あの赤い星も あの青い星も
When a life ends, the star falls and disappears.
命が尽きるとき
星も また流れて消えゆく
Please don't say that.
よしてくれ
走る岩よ
"Running Rock."
俺をそんな名で呼ばんでくれ
Don't call me by such a name!
His star is about to fall.
やつの星は流れようとしている
This is stupid.  I can't believe it.
ばかばかしい　信じられるか
Do not fear death.
死を恐れるな
Death is always at your side.
死は いつもそばにいる
When you show fear, it will spring at you faster than light.
恐れを見せた途端―
それは光よりも速く
飛びかかってくるだろう
恐れなければ―
If you do not show fear, it will only gently look over you.
それは ただ
優しく見守っているだけだ
Sir Vicious, I found this.
（シン）ビシャス様
これが
The woman's passport is inside it as well.
女のパスポートも入ったままです
Surely she cannot escape from this planet easily.
簡単に この星からは
出られないはず
A beast that has lost a place to go...
行き場をなくした獣か
He has nowhere to return to now.
やつはもう どこにも戻れない
He will come.
やつは来る
Spike, you...
スパイク お前…
Do you have anything to eat?
（スパイク）
なんか 食いもんないか？
腹ぺこなんだ
I'm starving.
The food you cook tastes horrible, as usual.
相変わらず
あんたの作る飯は まずいな
For that, you sure are eating a lot.
その割に随分 食ってるだろうが
Hunger is the best spice, they say.
（スパイク）
空腹は最高の調味料ってやつさ
Do you know a story that goes like this?
こんな話 知ってるか？
ああん？
There once was a tiger-striped cat.
（スパイク）あるトラ猫がいた
その猫は 好きでもない―
This cat died a million deaths and was reborn a million times...
いろんな飼い主たちに
飼われながら―
...and was owned by various people who he didn't care for.
100万回 死に
生き返って100万回 生きた
The cat wasn't afraid to die.
猫は死ぬのは怖くなかった
One day, the cat was a free cat, a stray cat.
あるとき猫は 自由な野良猫だった
He met a white female cat, and the two cats spent their days happily together.
そいつは白い雌猫に会い
２匹は一緒に幸せに暮らした
Years passed, and the white cat died of old age.
やがて月日がたち―
白い猫は年を取って死んじまった
The tiger-striped cat cried a million times, and then died.
トラ猫は100万回 泣いて
そして死んだ
It never came back to life.
もう二度と生き返らなかった
That's a good story...
いい話だ
（スパイク）俺は この話が嫌いだ
I hate that story.
I hate cats.
俺は猫が嫌いだ
That's what I thought.
だと思ったぜ
フッフ
ハッハッハッハ
Spike.
スパイク
（スパイク）うん？
Can I ask you one thing?
一つだけ聞いていいか
What?
（スパイク）何だ？
Is it for the woman?
女のためか？
There is nothing I can do for a dead woman.
（スパイク）死んだ女のために
できることなんてないさ
Where are you going?
（フェイ）どこ行くの？
Why are you going?
なんで行くの？
You told me once that the past didn't matter.
いつか あんた言ったわよね
“過去なんてどうでもいい”って
あんたのほうが過去に縛られてる
You're the one who's tied to their past!
この目を見ろ
Look at these eyes.
One of them is a fake, because I lost it in an accident.
事故でなくして
片っぽは作りもんだ
Since then, I have been seeing the past in one eye and the present in the other.
そん時から俺は
片方の目で過去を見て―
もう一方で今を見てた
I had believed that what I saw was not all of reality.
目に見えてるもんだけが
現実じゃない
そう思ってた
Don't tell me things like that.
（フェイ）そんな話 しないで
You never told me anything about yourself!
身の上話なんか
したことないくせに―
Don't tell me stuff like that now!
今 そんな話 しないでよ
覚めない夢でも
見てるつもりだったんだ
I thought I was watching a dream that I would never awake from.
フッ いつの間にか覚めちまってた
Before I knew it, the dream was all over.
My... memory came back.
（フェイ）私―
記憶 戻ったの
But... nothing good came out of it.
でも―
いいことなんて 何にもなかった
There was no place for me to return to.
帰る場所なんて
どこにもなかった
This was the only place I could go back to!
ここしか帰る場所がなかった
But now...
それなのに―
Where are you going?!
どこ行くの？
Why do you have to go?!
なんで行くの？
Are you telling me you're going to just throw your life away?!
わざわざ 命を
捨てに行くってわけ？
I'm not going there to die.
死にに行くわけじゃない
I'm going there to see if I really am alive.
俺が本当に生きてるかどうか
確かめに行くんだ
Shin!
シン！
Where's Vicious?
ビシャスは？
On the top floor.  This way.
最上階です　こちらへ
Shin!
シン！
Please defeat...  Vicious...
ビシャスを倒してください
Actually...
本当は―
...I wanted you to come back...
あなたに戻ってほしかった
So, you are finally awake.
（ビシャス）ようやく目が覚めたか
～
I told you before, Spike...
いつか言ったはずだ スパイク
～
...that I am the only one who can kill you.
“お前を殺せるのは俺だけだ”と
～
I'll return those words back to you, Vicious.
そのまま お前に返すぜ ビシャス
Either way, we were destined to end up like this.
どのみち お前とは
こうなる運命だ
Julia passed away.
ジュリアは逝っちまった
Let's end it all.
終わりにしようぜ
If that's your wish.
（ビシャス）望みどおりに
This is...
これは―
...a dream...
夢ね
Yeah...
（スパイク）ああ
Just a bad dream...
悪い夢さ
Bang!
バアン！
～